{
  "chapter": 4,
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is not an essential characteristic of NIST cloud model?",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Rapid elasticity",
        "Multi-tenancy",
        "Resource pooling",
        "Broad network access"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "NIST definition of cloud computing was published in the year of",
      "incorrect_answers": ["2007", "2009", "2011", "2013"],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "According to NIST definition, cloud computing is a",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Model", "Technology", "Paradigm", "Revolution"],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following service can only be accessed by a restricted number of people?",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Public cloud",
        "Community cloud",
        "Private cloud",
        "Both a & b"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the essential characteristics of cloud computing is not present in grid computing model?",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Rapid elasticity",
        "On-demand service",
        "Measured service",
        "Both a & b"
      ],
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "Public cloud can’t be deployed on-premises.",
      "incorrect_answers": ["False", "True"],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Private cloud can be deployed on-premises. This statement is",
      "incorrect_answers": ["False", "True"],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Users’ control over cloud environment is maximum in",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Public cloud",
        "Community cloud",
        "Private cloud",
        "Hybrid cloud"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Hybrid cloud is cheaper than private cloud. This statement is",
      "incorrect_answers": ["True", "False"],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following refers to the location and management of the cloud’s infrastructure?",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Application",
        "Services",
        "Deployment",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Which cloud deployment is managed by provider who resides offsite and is accessible to some restricted people?",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Private cloud",
        "Community cloud",
        "Public cloud",
        "Hybrid cloud"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "The number of actors mentioned in the NIST cloud computing reference architecture is",
      "incorrect_answers": ["4", "5", "6", "7"],
      "answer": 2
    }
  ]
}
